Again, I'll first think about how to standardize a single data point,
وأكرر، أفكرُ أولاً بشأن كيفية معايرة نقطة بيانات واحدة
say the value at position zero.
.ولنفترض أنها القيمة عند الموضع صفر
First, I'll calculate the distance of that value from the mean,
أولاً، سأحسب مسافة ،تلك القيمة من المتوسط
which I can do by subtracting.
.وهو ما يمكنني فعله باستخدام الطرح
Then to convert to a number of standard deviations,
ثم لتحويل عدد ،الانحرافات المعيارية
I'll need to divide by the standard deviation.
سأحتاج أولاً إلى القسمة على .الانحراف المعياري
And again, parentheses are important here.
،وأكرر مرة أخرى .من المهم استخدام الأقواس هنا
So this will calculate a single standardized value.
إذ سيحسب هذا .قيمة معيارية واحدة
And I could use a loop to standardize all the values, but
،ويمكنني استخدام تكرار حلقي لمعايرة جميع القيم ولكن بدلاً من هذا
instead I'm going to use vectorized operations.
سأستخدم .عمليات التحويل إلى رسومات المتجهات
Again, vectorized operations make the code to operate on an entire array very
وأكرر، توجه عمليات التحويل إلى رسومات المتجهات التعليمة البرمجية للعمل على صفيف كامل
similar to the code that operates on a single value.
بطريقة مشابهة تمامًا .للتعليمة البرمجية التي تعمل على قيمة واحدة
I'll simply change this variable from a single value
وسأغير هذا المتغير بكل بساطة من قيمة واحدة إلى
to the entire array of values.
.صفيف القيم بالكامل
Now values is the entire array, and the mean is still a single number.
والآن لا تزال القيم في الصفيف بالكامل و .المتوسط رقمًا واحدًا
So this subtraction subtracts the mean from each value in the array.
ولهذا ستُستخدم عملية الطرح هذه .لطرح المتوسط من كل قيمة في الصفيف
Then the standard deviation is still a single number, so
وبعد ذلك سيظل الانحراف المعياري رقمًا فرديًا ولهذا
this division divides each element of the array by the standard deviation.
تؤدي عملية القسمة هذه إلى قسمة كل عنصر من .الصفيف على الانحراف المعياري
And since this standardized all the values in the array, I will change this
وحيث إن هذه العملية أدت إلى معايرة جميع القيم في الصفيف، فسأغير هذا المتغير
variable to standardized values, and I'll delete this line.
،إلى القيم المعيارية .وسأحذف هذا السطر
And finally, I will return the standardized values.
،وأخيرًا .سأرجع القيم المعيارية